## **GABRIEL STROUP**

Kings Mountain, NC

Phone: 704-472-9763 | Email: gstroup11@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/glswebdev | GitHub: github.com/gstroup11

Portfolio: https://glsportfolio.netlify.app/

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer with a prominent background in problem solving and tech. As a full time Fiber Optics Technician for nearing 5 years I have developed a keen attention to detail when it comes to problem solving skills. Earning a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University Of North Carolina at Charlotte Coding Boot Camp; only amplified these skills. Known among coworkers to be super hard working, relentless, and executing every task to the best of my abilities.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Html, Css, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, ORM, MVC, NoSQL, and React.

#### **PROJECTS**

### Lyrx | github.com/gstroup11/Lyrx | https://lyrx-8c8792a2e8e6.herokuapp.com/

- **Summary:** A simple song searching app made with the intent of keeping music simple.
- Role: Project Manager, Api implementation, Controller routes, and backend database implementation.
- **Tools/Languages:** JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Lyrics API, Sessions, Dbeaver, Sequelize.

## SVG Logo Maker | github.com/gstroup11/SVG-Logo-Maker

- Summary: An application for freelance developers to quickly generate an SVG logo for their projects.
- Role: Sole Author
- Tools/Languages: JavaScript, Node.js, Inquirer, Jest

# The Mattress Shop! | github.com/gstroup11/The-Mattress-Shop | gstroup11.github.io/The-Mattress-Shop/

- **Summary:** A simple e-commerce website template for users to shop for a specified mattress.
- Role: Project Manager, JavaScript
- Tools/Languages: JavaScript, Html, Css, jQuery, Materialize Css, Google Maps API, YouTube Api

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Fiber Optics Technician TnT Optical Communications

2019-Present Kings Mountain, NC

As a field technician I worked day-in and day-out with various forms of fiber optics ranging from: Commercial Accounts, Residential Accounts, and Documentation. Learning skills ranging from: Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, and Leadership.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Promoted to a supervisorial tech and trained fellow coworkers.
- Assigned to work spares and troubleshoot directly from Hub sites (Spectrum)
- Successfully worked with a team of four splicers to successfully fix a total of 732 splices during an outage.
- Worked with various other contracting companies to resolve issues.

Line Cook
Dairy Queen
2020-2020
Shelby, NC

As a Line Cook I worked directly with customers on a day-to-day basis and prepared food quickly and efficiently for those customers.

### **Key Accomplishments:**

Worked directly with customers and learned about the customer service industry.

LifeGuard 2017-2018
Club Woodbridge Kings Mountain, NC

As a LifeGuard I was tasked with watching over club members as they were swimming and congregating around the pool. During this stint I learned many skills like: Risk Management, Critical Thinking and LifeSaving Techniques. Under this job I had a great deal of responsibility as pool goers where trusting me with keeping them safe.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Learned LifeSaving Techniques
- Worked without the supervision of a superior
- Maintained and kept the pool water clean, and surrounding areas
- Made and kept many friendships with club members.

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certificate: University of North Carolina at Charlotte, Charlotte, NC

Certificate of Criminal Justice: Cleveland Community College, Shelby, NC